<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Servator</title>
    <link>https://blog.vwzq.net/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Servator</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.vwzq.net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Computing with codes</title>
      <link>https://blog.vwzq.net/2021/02/computing-with-codes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vwzq.net/2021/02/computing-with-codes/</guid>
      <description>Recently I spent some time thinking about rowhammer and integrity issues in general. So, when a colleague asked about software-based mitigations to detect errors on faulty hardware, mainly in the context of CPUs in outer space suffering from cosmic rays corruption, it got me thinking.
I was aware that spaceships usually employ&amp;ndash;very expensive&amp;ndash;hardened CPUs, with special materials, shielding, and redundancy (both spatial, i.e., add resoures, and temporal, i.e., repeat computations). For instance, Perseverance, the recently arrived to Mars rover, runs on a RAD750 PowerPC CPU that costs ~$300,000; or critical systems (like plains or rockets) also tend to duplicate (or triplicate) resources and rely on some majority vote mechanism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cast me an alert(1)</title>
      <link>https://blog.vwzq.net/2021/01/cast-me-an-alert/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vwzq.net/2021/01/cast-me-an-alert/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to 2021! The future is today, and it is disappointing.
It is well known that any sane person, from time to time, opens the devtools&#39; console in a browser of his choice to start typing random JavaScript. At least this is what I do, though not as often as I used to.
The goal is unclear, as most times I do not even think or keep track of what I&amp;rsquo;m trying.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://blog.vwzq.net/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vwzq.net/about/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m Pepe Vila, although on the internets other conscious entities might know me as &amp;ldquo;cgvwzq&amp;rdquo; (or btoa(&#39;pepe&#39;).toLowerCase().slice(0,-2), yup, that&amp;rsquo;s why).
It is interesting how our brains end up assigning meaning to any random sequence of characters, no matter how alien and unpronounceable it seems at the begining. In fact natural language is just that, a bunch of random sequences of chars (and sounds) that we agree on and that have evolved (and continues doing so) to contain high levels of redundancy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World</title>
      <link>https://blog.vwzq.net/2020/12/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vwzq.net/2020/12/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>This is the first entry in this blog. I&amp;rsquo;m still trying to setup and understand Hugo, but since I&amp;rsquo;m here I guess I should share at least some tip.
I&amp;rsquo;m also setting up the new Macbook Air, and it seems that you need to manually specify whether to run an app with Rosetta (the x86_64 to arm64 translator) or not. As I&amp;rsquo;m going to be using both things, I duplicated the Terminal app, changed its name and icon (I had to do something silly with sips and iconutil), and set one with the option (go to Finder -&amp;gt; Applications -&amp;gt; Utilities, right click and Get Info, and set &amp;ldquo;Open using Rosetta&amp;rdquo;).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
