<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Servator</title>
    <link>https://blog.vwzq.net/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Servator</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.vwzq.net/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Side channels in web browsers</title>
      <link>https://blog.vwzq.net/2021/03/browser-side-channes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vwzq.net/2021/03/browser-side-channes/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been away from web browsers for some time now, but after the recent CSS Prime+Probe, SMASH, and Stephen Röttger&amp;rsquo;s spectre PoC I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help myself and had to spend some time catching up. Kudos to everyone involved! :)
First, I&amp;rsquo;m super happy to see that my work on replacement policies was justified, both SMASH and the Spectre PoC make super cool use of them, that&amp;rsquo;s something I&amp;rsquo;ve been expecting for some time now, and I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure we&amp;rsquo;ll see more of these tricks to squeeze caches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computing with codes</title>
      <link>https://blog.vwzq.net/2021/02/computing-with-codes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vwzq.net/2021/02/computing-with-codes/</guid>
      <description>Recently I spent some time thinking about rowhammer and integrity issues in general. So, when a colleague asked about software-based mitigations to detect errors on faulty hardware, mainly in the context of CPUs in outer space suffering from cosmic rays corruption, it got me thinking.
I was aware that spaceships usually employ&amp;ndash;very expensive&amp;ndash;hardened CPUs, with special materials, shielding, and redundancy (both spatial, i.e., add resoures, and temporal, i.e., repeat computations). For instance, Perseverance, the recently arrived to Mars rover, runs on a RAD750 PowerPC CPU that costs ~$300,000; or critical systems (like plains or rockets) also tend to duplicate (or triplicate) resources and rely on some majority vote mechanism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cast me an alert(1)</title>
      <link>https://blog.vwzq.net/2021/01/cast-me-an-alert/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vwzq.net/2021/01/cast-me-an-alert/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to 2021! The future is today, and it is disappointing.
It is well known that any sane person, from time to time, opens the devtools&#39; console in a browser of his choice to start typing random JavaScript. At least this is what I do, though not as often as I used to.
The goal is unclear, as most times I do not even think or keep track of what I&amp;rsquo;m trying.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World</title>
      <link>https://blog.vwzq.net/2020/12/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.vwzq.net/2020/12/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>This is the first entry in this blog. I&amp;rsquo;m still trying to setup and understand Hugo, but since I&amp;rsquo;m here I guess I should share at least some tip.
I&amp;rsquo;m also setting up the new Macbook Air, and it seems that you need to manually specify whether to run an app with Rosetta (the x86_64 to arm64 translator) or not. As I&amp;rsquo;m going to be using both things, I duplicated the Terminal app, changed its name and icon (I had to do something silly with sips and iconutil), and set one with the option (go to Finder -&amp;gt; Applications -&amp;gt; Utilities, right click and Get Info, and set &amp;ldquo;Open using Rosetta&amp;rdquo;).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
